competitionhunter.com 2016-03-14

# Competiton Hunter - Privacy Policy | Competition Hunter

  * Competiton Hunter - Privacy Policy

**Competition Hunter is a brand managed by DLG Limited (“DLG” or “We”).**   
DLG takes the issue of personal data and privacy extremely seriously and is registered as a Data Controller with the Information Commissioner’s Office, and as such your information will always be safeguarded through our adherence to the Data Protection Act 1998, and the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations (2003) to ensure that the information you provide to us is safe and only used for the purposes stated in the opt-in statement and this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy (together with our Terms of Use at www.CompetitionHunter.com/static/terms-of-use ) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”), the Data Controller is DLG Ltd. DLG Ltd. is a subsidiary of DM plc. Registered in England and Company No. 06742075. Registered Office: Green Heys, Walford Road, Ross on Wye, HR9 5DB.  
**  
Information we may collect from you  
**   
Competition Hunter is keen to ensure that the principals of our opt-in when your data is collected are clearly explained. The information you volunteer to Competition Hunter and that DLG holds about you, will be shared and used to appropriately target offers and marketing communication from Competition Hunter, from our clients, from our selected third party partners and from DLG and its other brands. Marketing communication may be through email, mailing, telemarketing and SMS/MMS, depending on which contact channel information you have volunteered. You may also receive marketing calls via automated voice broadcast over the telephone.

Some questions on our Registration Form and our own competitions are specific to our named sponsors, and by expressing a positive interest in their brand or products you are also agreeing to contact from them. By volunteering your phone number you are agreeing to telephone contact by these named sponsors. You may subsequently need to contact these named sponsor brands directly if in the future you decide to opt-out of further communication from these brands.

By registering on our site and entering competitions promoted by Competition Hunter or other brands within the DLG portfolio, we may collect and process the data you have provided. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our site, subscribing to our service, entering DLG branded competitions, posting material or requesting further services.

Your data may be used for analytical purposes. Your data may also be used in conjunction with data we may have received from other sources in order to improve personalised and targeted communications, and we may share information with other companies for the same reason.

Your data may be shared and combined with other companies who hold your personal data, and we may use information from other sources to add to data we already hold. This information may help us to improve our ability to service your needs on a personalised basis, by helping us to learn more about you and your purchasing habits and allowing us to let you know about offers you might be interested in.

Your data may be used for data validation, enhancement, information verification, suppression, tracing and to the extent permitted by law, individual reference or lookup services, by DLG and third parties.

DLG may also receive information about you when you register on one of our affiliate or partner sites, or when you take part in a special promotion for one of these affiliates or partners. If you have registered with Competition Hunter through one of our third party partner sites, it is possible that the third party site may also retain your data, but only in accordance with the terms and conditions as published by them on their site.

Please Note: Our site contains links to external websites of companies hosting competitions, partners, partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.  
**  
Where we store your personal data  
**   
The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.  
**  
Uses made of the information  
**   
We use information held about you in the following ways:

• To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.

• To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes.

• To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.

• To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so. To notify you about changes to our service.

We may also use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you about these by post or telephone.

By registering on Competition Hunter you are agreeing that Competition Hunter and carefully selected third parties can contact you by e-mail, phone, post or SMS with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale to you.

If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please contact our Data Compliance Department.  
**  
Disclosure of your information  
**   
We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

• In the event that we sell any business or assets we may disclose your personal data to the prospective buyer of such business or assets.

• If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of DLG, our customers, or others. (This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction).

## Your rights

**  
Personal Data  
**   
You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by contacting us at:

DLG Limited, Compliance Department, Ground Floor, 64 Clarendon Road, Watford, WD17 1DA

Alternatively, you can email consumerdataprotection@dlg.co.uk  
**  
Deregistration / Suppression  
**   
You can unsubscribe from Competition Hunter email communications at any time by clicking on the link at the foot of any email correspondence. Your details will be suppressed, Competition Hunter will send no further emails and your details will no longer be passed onto any third parties for the uses described in this Privacy Policy. Your details will then be suppressed and Competition Hunter will send no further email communication.

To request suppression from DLG completely, please write to us at the address above, or email consumerdataprotection@dlg.co.uk  
**  
Subject Access Request  
**   
You can also request to know what personal information DLG holds about you, by writing in person to us at the address above asking for subject access request (you will need to provide us with the following information: name, address and email address). There is a £10 processing charge to cover the administration costs (please make cheques payable to DLG Limited).  
**  
Data security  
**   
Although we endeavour to ensure the security of all correspondence, the Internet is not a 100% secure medium. Therefore, we are unable to guarantee the security of any data you send electronically to Competition Hunter and are unable to accept responsibility for any loss or damage experienced through any loss of confidentiality of your information.  
**  
Right of transfer  
**   
Should Competition Hunter or DLG choose to sell or transfer business assets, it is possible that the information we hold may be transferred as part of the transaction. Competition Hunter or DLG may choose to retain a copy of the information post sale or transfer.

## IP addresses and cookies

**  
What is a Cookie?  
**   
A cookie is a small file that a website downloads to your computer. Cookies allow websites to tailor their operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by remembering information about your preferences.  
**  
THE COOKIES WE USE ON COMPETITION HUNTER  
** **  
Essential cookies  
**   
These are vital for the running of our services on our websites. Without the use of these cookies parts of our websites would not function. For example, cookies are needed to log into the site, set preferences and allow you to keep track of what competitions you have entered.  
**  
Analytical Cookies  
**   
These cookies collect information about how you use our website and enable us to improve the way it works. For example, we can monitor the most frequently visited pages and most frequently entered competitions. This allows us to identify how you interact with our websites in order to make improvements and optimise your user experience.  
**  
Tracking and advertising cookies  
**   
We use these cookies to provide advertisements that are more relevant to your interests. Cookies remember the websites you have previously visited and the adverts displayed on our site could be based on what you have previously been looking at. For example: You may be looking online to book a holiday to Florida and have visited various travel sites, when you visit another website within the same advertising network, the website might show you an advert related to holiday in Florida.  
**  
Tracking tags and tracking URLs  
**   
This enables us to track and record simple actions. For example: we use tags in our email newsletters to check that it was successfully delivered and then use tracking tags and URLS to verify any clicks on the links in our newsletters. We can use this information to identify whether our newsletters are being opened and determine what content is of interest so we can make improvements.  
**  
Third party advertisers  
**   
We add third party competitions and display third party advertisements on our site. Quite often by clicking through to third party sites, these sites will often contain cookies. We do not control third-party cookies. You should make sure you are aware of how third parties will use cookies by checking their cookie policy.  
**  
Managing cookies  
**   
Most modern browsers are set to accept cookies by default, but you can change your settings to notify you when a cookie is being set or updated, or to block cookies altogether. Please consult the “Help” section of your browser.

Please note that by blocking any or all cookies you may not have access to certain features, and content available on our websites.  
**  
Useful links  
**   
We are keen to promote the best interests of consumers and how their personal data is used and employ best practices on our websites. If you would like to know more about how your information can be utilised, how you can restrict its use, who has access and a wide range of other aspects, we suggest you refer to the following sources:

• The Information Commissioner; www.ico.gov.uk

• The Citizens Advice Bureau; www.adviceguide.org.uk
